

GRADUATE STUDENT RESEARCHER

200 University Ave West, Waterloo, ON, Canada N2L 3G1

□ (+1) 437-779-9277 | ☑ nalin.chhibber@uwaterloo.ca | ♣ http://nalinc.github.io | □ nalinc | □ nalinchhibber

Overview ____

I am a research based Master's student in David R. Cheriton School of Computing Science at the University of Waterloo. My research interests lies on the intersection of Human-AI Interaction and Intelligent User Interfaces. I am currently studying how to effectively combine Human and Artificial Intelligence to argument teachers in K-12 classrooms.

Education

M.Math. in Computer Science

ADVISOR: EDITH LAW (HUMAN COMPUTER INTERACTION GROUP)

B.Tech. in Computer Science and Engineering

ADVISORS: CHARU ARORA (MSIT), GOPAL KRISHNA PATRA (CSIR-4PI)

University of Waterloo, Ontario, Canada

Sept 2017 - Present

Indraprastha University, New Delhi, India

Aug. 2010 - Jul. 2014

Experience _____

Google Summer of Code

Waterloo, Canada

STUDENT DEVELOPER FOR AIMACODE

May. 2018 - Aug. 2018

Worked with Peter Norvig (Director of Research at Google) to design and implement a student-instructor workflow for a new platform. The platform hosts aima-exercises for the fourth edition of the book 'Artificial Intelligence: A Modern Approach'

University Of Waterloo
Waterloo, Canada

GRADUATE RESEARCH AND TEACHING ASSISTANT

Sept. 2017 - Present

As a Graduate Research and Teaching Assistant, I have assisted course instructors from advance undergrad courses (CS 330, CS 490, CS 349, CS 348) by automating assignments, grading, proctoring and conducting weekly personal consultations for students.

Compro Technologies New Delhi, India

FULLSTACK SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Oct. 2014 - Aug. 2017

I was part of the primary development team and worked on the full technological stack for web and mobile applications. I was involved in creating next generation e-learning products (e-reader, courseware) for better user engagement and achieve pure learning vision.

CERN, GS-Scientific Information Service

Geneva. Switzerland

SUMMER STUDENT INTERN

June. 2014 - Aug. 2014

Worked at GS-Scientific Information Services group to enrich exiting metadata with data from other libraries and integrate changes into the open source software 'invenio'. Updated metadata was made available on CDS (CERN Document Server) after the internship.

CSIR-Fourth Paradigm Institute

Bangalore, India

RESEARCH INTERN, SPARK

Aug. 2013 - Dec. 2013

Worked with Gopal Krishna Patra (Principal Scientist, CSIR 4PI) to create a secure cryptosystem inspired by chaos theory. This was a part of CSIR-SPARK (Student Program for Advancement in Research Knowledge).

Skills_

Languages

C/C++ JavaScript sql Shell Scripting HTML/CSS



Typealike: Typing-Friendly Command Postures

Glasgow, Scotland

SUBMITTED TO ACM CONFERENCE ON HUMAN FACTORS IN COMPUTING SYSTEMS (SIGCHI)

Conference in May. 2019

Nalin Chhibber, Edith Law, Daniel Vogel

Expression of Curiosity in Social Robots: Design, Perception, and Effects on Behaviour

Glasgow, Scotland

SUBMITTED TO ACM CONFERENCE ON HUMAN FACTORS IN COMPUTING SYSTEMS (SIGCHI)

Conference in May. 2019

Jessy Ceha, **Nalin Chhibber**, Edith Law, Dana Kulic, Joslin Goh, Pierre-Yves Oudeyer, Corina McDonald

Human Perception of Surprise: A User Study

Michigan, USA

Workshop on Computational Surprise in 41th ACM Conference on Research and Development in Information Retrieval (SIGIR)

Jul. 2018

Nalin Chhibber, Rohail Syed, Mengqiu Teng, Joslin Goh, Kevyn Collins-Thompson, Edith Law

Prototype Tasks: Improving Crowdsourcing Results through Rapid, Iterative Task Design

Quebec, Canada

PRESENTED ON 5TH AAAI CONFERENCE ON HUMAN COMPUTATION AND CROWDSOURCING (HCOMP)

Oct. 2017

Snehalkumar 'Neil' Gaikwad, **Nalin Chhibber**, Vibhor Sehgal, Alipta Ballav, Catherine Mullings, Ahmed Nasser, Angela Richmond-Fuller, Aaron Gilbee, Dilrukshi Gamage, Mark Whiting, Sharon Zhou, Sekandar Matin, Senadhipathige Niranga, Shirish Goyal, Dinesh Majeti, Preethi Srinivas, Adam Ginzberg, Kamila Mananova, Karolina Ziulkoski, Jeff Regino, Tejas Sarma, Akshansh Sinha, Abhratanu Paul, Christopher Diemert, Mahesh Murag, William Dai, Manoj Pandey, Rajan Vaish and Michael S. Bernstein

Crowd Guilds: Worker-led Reputation and Feedback on Crowdsourcing Platforms

Oregon, USA

In proceedings of the 20th ACM Conference on Computer Supported Cooperative Work and Social Computing (CSCW)

Feb. 2017

Mark E. Whiting, Dilrukshi Gamage, Snehalkumar 'Neil' Gaikwad, Aaron Gilbee, Shirish Goyal, Alipta Ballav, Dinesh Majeti, **Nalin Chhibber**, Angela Richmond-Fuller, Freddie Vargus, Tejas Seshadri Sarma, Varshine Chandrakanthan, Teogenes Moura, Mohamed Hashim Salih, Gabriel Bayomi Tinoco Kalejaiye, Adam Ginzberg, Catherine Mullings, Yoni Dayan, Kristy Milland, Henrique Orefice, Jeff Regino, Sayna Parsi, Kunz Mainali, Vibhor Sehgal, Sekandar Matin, Akshansh Sinha, Rajan Vaish, Michael S. Bernstein

Boomerang: Aligning Worker and Requester Incentives on Crowdsourcing Platforms

Tokyo, Japan

IN PROCEEDINGS OF THE 29TH ACM SYMPOSIUM ON USER INTERFACE SOFTWARE AND TECHNOLOGY (UIST)

Oct. 2016

Snehalkumar (Neil) S. Gaikwad, Durim Morina, Adam Ginzberg, Catherine Mullings, Shirish Goyal, Dilrukshi Gamage, Christopher Diemert, Mathias Burton, Sharon Zhou, Mark Whiting, Karolina Ziulkoski, Alipta Ballav, Aaron Gilbee, Senadhipathige S. Niranga, Vibhor Sehgal, Jasmine Lin, Leonardy Kristianto, Angela Richmond-Fuller, Jeff Regino, **Nalin Chhibber**, Dinesh Majeti, Sachin Sharma, Kamila Mananova, Dinesh Dhakal, William Dai, Victoria Purynova, Samarth Sandeep, Varshine Chandrakanthan, Tejas Sarma, Sekandar Matin, Ahmed Nasser, Rohit Nistala, Alexander Stolzoff, Kristy Milland, Vinayak Mathur, Rajan Vaish, Michael S. Bernstein

Synchronization of Chaos in Multiple Three-Dimensional Chaotic Maps

Langkawi, Malaysia

In proceedings of IEEE International Symposium on Technology Management and Emerging Technologies (ISTMET)

Aug. 2015

Nalin Chhibber, Gopal Patra

Enriching the metadata on Cern Document Server

Geneva, Switzerland

CERN DOCUMENT SERVER INTERNAL NOTE

Aug. 2014

Nalin Chhibber, Javier Martin Montull, Tullio Basaglia, Jens Vigen

Projects _

Curiosity Notebook: Framework to effectively combine Human and Artificial Intelligence to assist teachers in K-12 classrooms. The idea is to augment human teachers (not replace them) by means of virtual teaching assistants that can keep students engaged even outside classrooms. This is an active research project led by professor Edith Law in the University of Waterloo HCI lab.

Typealike Interactions: Typealike is an input technique that uses computer vision and machine learning to identify simple hand postures over the keyboard surface. It supports hand postures which can augment keyboard operations by triggering commands or activating additional input modes without disturbing the natural typing flow.

StoryKart: An educational platform to craft and share interactive stories. Includes simple drag-drop interface with script-editor to create animated stories. This project was inspired from Scratch: the visual programming language, but specifically focused on strengthening story building skills in kids.

Cosmic Shooters, **MarkdownJS**, **Tweebbles** and **ChatJS** are some other projects I built. I am also active on online developer communities like Stackoverflow (6000+ reputation, 25 badges, 5 bounties) and contribute to open-source projects (KDE, AIMACode, Stanford Crowdresearch, Python FOSSEE TBC).